CURRICULUM VITAE

Name: Stuart Simmons

Address: 8 Barnes Ave,

Burwood, Victoria 3125

Phone: (03) 9888 9865

0459 919 818

Email: stuart.simmons@optusnet.com.au

STRENGTHS

I have very good rapport with customers and in turn develop strong relationships. These relationships have, over time, built a loyal customer base for the companies I have worked for. Evaluating customers' wants, needs, assessing financial justification and assisting customers in making sound decisions.

Maintaining strong relationships with customers to assist in future sales

I have an ability to quickly evaluate problems and implement solutions for example, managing limited resources on large demanding projects. I have a keen eye for detail and I am able to foresee potential problems in advance.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

AVIA AVIATION PTY LTD

October 2016 - Present

Cirrus Melbourne Aircraft Sales Manager

Develop aircraft sales within the company including sales to private buyers, development of relationships with large flying schools and fleet evaluation.

Complete sales contracts, registration transfers and registration of new aircraft as required.

Develop and maintain relationship with principal OEM.

Monthly sales reports to CEO and principal OEM.

Plan and organise Cirrus Tour for the represented region including involvement with prominent Airshows and Aero Clubs.

Responsible for marketing and advertising across print media, email campaigns and post.

Develop and maintain a company budget for Aircraft Sales and Avia flying school.

AIRFLITE PTY LTD

October 2012 - October 2016

Business Development Manager – Aircraft Sales

Aircraft Sales Manager

Develop aircraft sales within the company including sales to private buyers, development of large flying schools, fleet evaluation and upgrade plans with large companies.

Develop and maintain relationship with principal OEM's.

Develop leasing arrangements with flying schools across Australia.

07/03/18 Page 2 of 6

Monthly sales reports to CEO and principal OEM's.

Organise all aspects of the bi-annual "Avalon Airshow"

Organise and participate in static and flying demonstrations for aero club fly-in's.

Organise demonstration tours of aircraft across Australia.

Maintain the integrity of Airflite owned and leased fleet aircraft in Melbourne including maintenance scheduling, renegotiating new lease agreement and aircraft upgrades.

Responsible for marketing and advertising across print media, email campaigns and post.

Importing and exporting aircraft and associated parts

Development of spare parts supply to the RAAF through an associated OEM including stocking levels, negotiating pricing and delivery.

HADEN & CUSTANCE LTD

September 2011 – October 2012

Technical Sales Manager

Maintain existing client base and develop a new customer base outside of the existing industry.

Develop technical solutions to customer requirements including robotics and factory automation.

Internal sales to

Financially evaluate and expand the current presence of the company within Australia.

AUTOMATION INNOVATION

September 2010 - September 2011

Business Development Manager

Develop new customers and diversify the customer base away from the automotive industry. Sales targets for 2010/11 financial year were achieved with new customers in a variety of industries including sign making, bio-medical, solar and composite materials. Strategies include networking through existing contacts and cold calling leading to the building of new relationships.

HEADLAND MACHINERY

February 2009 – September 2010

Develop a new business unit to sell KUKA robotics to the Australian and NZ market. KUKA robotics is a well known European robot. Duties included marketing, business development, database management, relationship building, negotiation with principal, event management and future direction. I was able to grow the brand name within Australia utilising the existing database and offering service incentives as well as an old for new program. The brand now has some significant market share and is steadily growing.

JOHN HART PTY LTD

August 1994 – October 2008

John Hart is a machine tool, special products and factory automation systems supplier employing over 60 people Australia wide. John Hart comprises of five main areas -: machine tool and measuring systems, customer support, technology, second hand machine tools and automation and robotics. John Hart is the agent for Yamazaki Mazak, Fanuc Robots and various other engineering suppliers. John Hart Technology supplies software and IT services both in-house and to external customers.

JOHN HART EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE

July 2002 - September 2008

Report to the executive on matters concerning John Hart Automation and Robotics Research the opportunities for the company in new growth markets such as China and USA Report and recommend changes / improvements to technology and IT 07/03/18 Page 3 of 6

Participate and recommend changes concerning the company

JOHN HART AUTOMATION AND ROBOTICS - GENERAL MANAGER JOHN HART TECHNOLOGY (DALIAN) CO. LTD. - GENERAL MANAGER

March 2008 - September 2008

Report directly to General Manager of John Hart

Oversee the development and growth of Australia

Full financial responsibility of the Automation and Robotics division

Manage the Australian team of an Operations Manager and 12 staff

Develop and implement a business plan to start a new company in Dalian, China including renting of factory, liaising with Chinese Government Departments and Accountants

Sales to both foreign owned and Chinese owned companies within China. Companies included Bosch, Yamazaki, First Automotive Company, Lincoln Electric, Sandvik

Employ and manage a Chinese team of six including: -

- 1 x Australian manager (expatriate)
- 4 x Chinese engineers
- 1 x Office administrator

JOHN HART AUTOMATION AND ROBOTICS - MANAGER

July 2002- March 2008

Report directly to CEO

Manage a team of 12 including

3 x sales engineers (1 x sales manager)2 x applications engineer1 x project manager2 x electrical design engineer

3 x designer and project engineers

1 x personal assistant

Resource management.

Manage major accounts and directly sell to major clients. Develop these relationships

Source suppliers and reduce costs by utilising overseas suppliers in China.

Look for overseas business opportunities

Open a new Technology Centre and Training facility

Analyse customer requirements and recommend automated solutions

JOHN HART TECHNOLOGY - MANAGER

February 2000- July 2002

Report directly to CEO

Manage a team of 4 qualified engineers

Create and manage a business plan and budget

Keep the John Hart group informed of new technology including machine tools, cutting tools and cutting techniques

Conduct customer seminars demonstrating John Hart products

Manage IT services for the John Hart Group

JOHN HART ASSISTANT BRANCH MANAGER - VICTORIAN BRANCH

February 1998 - February 2000

Manage a team of service and application engineers – approximately 20 people

Management of all Victorian projects (BTR, Holdens etc)

Organise and project manage trade shows and in-house exhibitions for John Hart.

Organise training courses for John Hart employees

Oversee the installation of new machine tools and provide appropriate customer training

07/03/18 Page 4 of 6

Train John Hart Application Engineers in new machining technologies

Oversee time management for branch personnel

Assist with IT issues

Organise preventative maintenance schedules

Establish documentation and process data for all new projects

JOHN HART - SITE SUPERVISOR

August 1997 - February 1998

Senior Applications Engineer – Holden's site

August 1996 - August 1997

Commissioning of the cylinder head manufacturing facility at Holdens – Hüller Hille Agile line

JOHN HART - APPLICATIONS ENGINEER

August 1994 - August 1996

Commissioning of the steering knuckle manufacturing facility at Mitsubishi Motors Adelaide.

CHEVIOT MANUFACTURING (ARROWCREST GROUP)

August 1992 - August 1994

Machine shop supervisor

Supervise 14 production people over 3 shifts

Organise daily production schedules

Process engineering & CNC programming of new products

New capital equipment purchases

Liaise with a design team on future design improvements

Organise preventative and breakdown maintenance

Organise and maintain consumable stocks for the machine shop

ROH INDUSTRIES (ARROWCREST GROUP)

Senior CNC Programmer – Alloy wheels

January 1988 - July 1989

Programming of new alloy wheels for the ROH alloy wheel machine shop

Documentation of process for quality standards (Q1)

Development of new tooling to reduce cycle times

Fitting and machining apprenticeship

January 1984 - January 1988

Apprentice of the Year – ROH Industries 1988

07/03/18 Page 5 of 6

EDUCATION:

Commercial Pilots Licence 2012
Multi-Engine Command Instrument Rating 2014

Melbourne Flight Training Moorabbin, Victoria

Private Pilots Licence 2008

Melbourne Flight Training Moorabbin, Victoria

Fitter & Turner Apprenticeship 1984 ~ 1988

Regency Park TAFE, South Australia ROH Wheels, Woodville, South Australia

SOFTWARE COMPETENCY

Computer/PC

Microsoft Windows (All) and Office Suite

Microsoft Visio

Microsoft Project

Microsoft Visual Basic

Windows networking

In addition, I am competent in a number of Industry software packages for 3D Design, Robots, CNC Machines and Measurement.

Aviation Systems

 ${\sf Garmin~G1000,~G2000,~G3000,~GNS~430,~530,~650,~750}$

COURSES:

Training methods

Level 2 first aid (Current)

Sales Advantage - Dale Carnegie
Spin selling - Huthwaite
Leadership and Interpersonal skills - AIM

Time Management Supporting the Sale

Occupational Health and Safety/ Risk Management

Methods of Instruction for On-The-Job Training

07/03/18 Page 6 of 6

REFERENCES

Referees available upon request

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

Scouts
Cycling
Camping / 4wd